Vibhuti Maheshwari

Software Engineer

A skilled and solution-driven Software Engineer with over 2.5 YOE in developing, testing, and supervising the entire development life cycle(SDLC) to deliver high-quality software. My expertise lies in utilizing technologies like Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Liquibase, SQL and others to ensure successful project outcomes, from initial analysis to the final product.

vibhutimaheshwari03@gmail.com
in linkedin.com/in/vibhutimaheshwari

7060175579

github.com/vibhuti03

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Optum

06/2021 - Present

Associate Software Engineer (06/2021 - 02/2023)

Achievements/Tasks

- Exposed 10+ REST APIs for cross-functional web applications based on microservices architecture using Springboot, Hibernate & MS SQL.
- Demonstrated versatility by designing, coding, database engineering and deployment of over 5 major projects.
- Designed the system to handle ~2k to ~10k requests with autoscaling without causing business impacts.
- Led the offshore agile team of 4, ensuring delivery of projects resulting in overall savings of \$3.3M.
- Developed and managed the DevOps aspect of the system inclusive of continuous integration & deployment and containerization.
- Maintain code quality and resolved 1k+ defects by analyzing and debugging the existing code.

Data Science Intern

Society of Al

06/2020 - 09/2020

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed 4 projects using technologies like ML, Data Analysis and Al using Python.
- Shared knowledge and insights with the Data Science team.
- Been the team lead of 3 projects based on AI, CV and ML.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Recipe Sharing

- Project Link
- Platform to share recipes among users.
- Users can submit a recipe and/or fetch a required recipe or select one from the pool of recipes available.
- o Technologies Java, SpringBoot, Hibernate, MySQL

EDUCATION

B. Tech Computer Science & EngineeringDIT University, Dehradun

08/2017 - 05/2021 8.13

SKILLS



ACHIEVEMENTS

20+ Bravo Recognitions at Optum *For team collaboration and leadership*

Awarded for Performance at SOAI

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified in Advanced Java & Springboot GeeksForGeeks

FSE Java Certification

FSE DevOps Certification

Certified in Big Data Analytics & Python Brillica Services Pvt. Ltd.

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency